In just over two months, I went from
posting my very first video on a
completely new channel all the way to
making over $47,000
with yesterday being my best day yet
where I made over $6,000 in a single
day. But I'm about to be leaking
everything. I am genuinely going to leak
how I came up with the niche. I'm going
to be leaking how I make the videos in
under 10 minutes and most importantly,
how I don't get demonetized posting AI
slop. So, listen up because I'm about to
be giving you guys some
never-beforeheard strategies that I came
up with. And just before we get started,
I'm about to prove to you guys I'm
legit. I'm leaking my channel here. I'm
not gatekeeping anything. I can even
show you guys that this is in Canadian
dollars. If I change it to another
currency, as you see, the currency
changes. Now, there's a common
misconception that people don't
typically have a very high RPM when
posting AI slop. But, I'm about to show
you guys something here. The reason I
make so much money is because my RPM is
insane. If you look at this video, I had
a $24.50
RPM, which is on a 28 minute long video.
That's incredible. So, how did I get an
RPM like that? Well, let me show you
guys exactly what I'm posting. This
right here is Marcus Graves.
>> That is the only thing.
>> This is my AI avatar, and he simply just
talks about finance. This video was
called Never Keep This Much Money in
Your Bank Account: IRS watching in 2026.
And it got over 300,000 views, meaning
it clearly made me over $6,000
alone. So, what exactly is this video?
Well, let me tell you that these videos
are super simple to make. The first part
is simply just an AI avatar,
>> which is Marcus Graves, and then the
second part is the motion graphics,
which are just simple motion graphics
like this. And I'm about to show you the
system that I use to put it all together
into one process that makes the AI
avatar and the motion graphics and
everything in one place. But before we
can get into actually creating a video,
we need to figure out what video we are
going to create. What is our niche? Now,
even though this part should be really
easy, all of you guys mess this up. The
first thing that you guys need to
understand is that a niche is a video
idea. So, I don't like to think of niche
as a category like the, you know, a lot
of people like to say the American
Finance niche. That's what I'm in. and
other people are in the doctor niche.
But no, that's not the way you should be
thinking about it. You should think
about your niche as a video idea. For
example, this AI doctor with this
thumbnail style where there's like a
picture and this blue background and him
standing there and titles that look
similar to this, that is a niche in and
of itself. So, can you just copy a
niche? No. Cuz this is what will happen
if you just try to copy a niche like
this. As you can see, this got 1.5
million views 2 weeks ago, but this only
got 19 views. So, as you can see,
copying niches will not work. I'll give
you another great example of that. You
see my channel, I get great views. In
fact, as you can see, if I go to my
popular videos, this one was just from 3
days ago. This one was from a month ago.
Both of these were viral videos. This
one got 500,000 views. This one got
600,000 views. These were two of my
biggest earners. Each of them generating
me around $10,000.
However, if we go to this guy's channel,
we can see he did the exact same thing.
He did the basically the same thumbnail,
basically the same title. If mine works
so well, why didn't his work? Well,
that's simply just because YouTube can
detect copycat content. If they see that
someone is just clearly blatantly
copying another person's niche, they're
not going to give them any views because
the other person has already satisfied
their audience. They don't need more
clones of them. So, if you can't just
copy someone's niche or someone's video
ideas, how are you going to do it? Well,
it's very simple. What you want to do
instead of just copying someone is you
copy two people. You combine viral
videos. Here's exactly how I blew up
with my very first video on the Marcus
Graves channel. As you can see, if I go
to oldest videos, literally the second
video I posted blew up and got 580,000
views. And here's how I came up with the
video idea for it. During my research
for this channel, I found these two
videos. This one was a video on the
$10,000 bank rule, but what I noticed is
that it had a very bad thumbnail and a
very bad title. Now, this video was on a
much more commonly talked about topic,
the borrow until you die strategy. There
were already tons and tons of videos
about the strategy, yet this person
managed to stand out and get a bunch of
views. And that's because they had a
really good title and a really good
thumbnail. This person had a really good
title and a really good thumbnail, but
in an oversaturated topic. And this
person found a completely brand new
topic that performed super well even
without a good title and thumbnail. So,
what did I do? I stole the best parts of
each one. I stole the topic here, the
$10,000 bank rule because that was the
amazing topic that worked so well. And I
stole the format, right? The packaging,
the the title and the thumbnail. This
this channel used the borrow until you
die strategy the IRS does not want you
to know. The IRS does not want you to
know is their format. It just sounds so
good. Why doesn't the IRS want me to
know about this? It's creating a
curiosity gap within the title. So, I
use that within my title. The IRS
doesn't want you to understand this
$10,000 bank rule. Same thing. Why
doesn't the IRS want not want me to
understand this $10,000 bank rule? So,
by using a great title and a great
thumbnail and a great topic,
$600,000 views easily. Now, what you
guys need to understand, can a category
be too saturated? Can I just make more
American Finance accounts? No. Trust me,
I've tried. You can't make more American
Finance accounts. This has been overpop
populated with AI avatars and you will
no longer be able to blow up an account
in something like this. How do you test
if a category is too saturated? Well,
take for example this account, Dr.
Waterling. As you can see, Dr. Waterling
gets a ton of views. They got 1.6
million views on this video right here 3
weeks ago. 1.6 million views. Now, does
that mean just anyone can copy this?
Well, a good way to test if a doctor
niche, right, in this case, or a doctor
category as we should call it, the
medical category, are there already too
many AI avatars? Well, a good way to
test that is we take this title and we
just copy it into the search bar and we
see are a lot of people already copying
them and already making AI doctors.
As you can see, Dr. Waterling has a lot
of copycats. There are literally
hundreds of videos now within the
medical doctor niche. In fact, it's even
more oversaturated than the AI finance
niche. So, whatever you do, do not hop
into a category like this. Do not hop
into the medical category because you
are simply just going to get put in with
all the slob content and you are never
going to be able to get any views. So,
if that's how you decide that a category
is bad, then how do you decide that a
category is actually good? Well, simply
just scroll, find something naturally,
and just look through it and see how
much AI competition there is. Here's a
good example. The other day, I was
scrolling and I found this. This is a
real woman posting real videos um with
home care tips, right? And as you can
see, every single one of her videos are
getting good views. Almost all of these
have 100,000 with some of them having
over a million. Now, that is very
incredible, especially for such a new
channel that only started posting 3
months ago. So clearly these videos have
something to them. Clearly this is a
huge potential, you know, style to hop
into. Now we want to look at the market.
Is this market oversaturated? Well, I've
actually taken a look around this exact
market. And while there are a whole lot
of people doing it with other formats,
they're maybe posting with 2D animations
and all types of stuff. Not a lot of
people are doing it with AI avatars just
yet. So I definitely think we are about
to see a ton of AI avatars hopping into
home care niches like this. So, if we
find a good category like home care, all
you would have to do is scroll for hours
until you find two complimentary viral
videos that you can steal the best parts
of and just turn it into one awesome
video within that category. And just
like that, you've created an entire new
niche. You know, you don't want to be
copying what someone else is doing. But
now that you've invented your entirely
new package, YouTube will see that. and
YouTube will see that you're posting not
only original content, but since you
know that the category is good and
hopefully you're good at YouTube,
YouTube will immediately push you out
because they think you're posting
something original and something that is
actually getting people to watch. So,
now that you have a couple viral video
ideas to get your channel started, what
is your AI avatar going to look like?
Who is going to be the person behind the
channel? So, let's create an AI avatar.
What we're going to do is we're just
going to go to AI and we're going to an
AI image generator and we're going to
give them a prompt. Let's say, you know,
create me a woman sitting at her desk
and the camera POV is here and
everything, right? We're gonna give a
long prompt and it's going to generate
us something like this, which isn't bad,
right? Wrong. It's actually horrible.
And here's why. Even though this looks
pretty realistic, this image probably
has AI watermarks all over it. Now, when
YouTube sees this, YouTube can very
possibly detect these AI watermarks with
their AI tracking system and immediately
flag this as AI generated content, which
is much, much, much more likely to get
you demonetized.
Now, how do you get YouTube to think
you're a real person? Well, very simple.
You don't make you don't steal a real
person, but you steal a real person's
background image. You go to a random
YouTube video. Sorry, whoever this guy
is. You take their background and you
simply replace them with a completely
new character. The prompt for the AI
image generator would be something like
replace the man in the first reference
image with a blah blah blah blah blah
and then you describe the second man.
Then you will get an image like this.
Now even though this guy is still AI,
YouTube won't specifically detect him
using their watermark system because the
background is realistic. When YouTube's
doing their AI detection, the background
won't have any AI watermark. So
oftentimes YouTube won't realize that
it's AI and let it fly right under the
radar until you have a huge account. So
now that you have an ultra realistic AI
avatar, how do you get an ultra
realistic AI voice? Very simple. You
clone someone else's voice. It's
honestly that simple, guys. Use either
11 Labs voice cloning or Miniax voice
cloning and just take an audio file of
someone else's voice from a YouTube
video and clone it. This sounds very
mean, but trust me guys, this is
important. I think your voice is
probably the biggest factor that YouTube
looks at when deciding whether to
demonetize a channel. So, let's say
we've gone ahead and made our AI avatar
and we've gone ahead and taken a voice
clip from someone else. How do we
actually make the full video now? Well,
this is the fun part. We're going to be
using two different softwares. one
called Rookcast and one called Hen. I
actually like to use a combination of
the two. You could technically only use
Rookcast. However, I would suggest using
them both because it will be much
cheaper and I'll show you why. But first
off, let's go ahead and create our
virtual character. You go to avatars and
you go create virtual character and you
upload photo. Okay, so I've just
uploaded my photo. Let's say this is
going to be my AI avatar. I'm going to
name her Lisa Graves as I always use the
last name Graves in any of my channels.
So, if you guys ever see a channel with
the last name Graves, just so you know,
that's me. Anyway, we get all the
settings down here and we go continue.
Now, from here, this is where you would
go click clone your voice and upload
audio. However, for this case, I
actually already have an audio prepared
that I'm going to select. All right, so
now that we've created an avatar within
Hen, this next part is going to be done
within Rookcast. And I'll show you why
we did the hijen part first in just a
second. What we're going to do is when
we get to Rookcast, we have these two
options. Either open sandbox or use a
preset. Remember guys, this is very
important. If you use the sandbox, you
should be experienced and you should be
going for a very like different channel
style. So something that can't just be
done as a preset because using this is
going to cost a lot more money just to
set up your channel. You're going to
have to talk back and forth with the
agent and it's going to have to use
logic to figure out exactly the workflow
of your channel, right? It could be
creating AI B-roll here and doing this
here and all types of stuff. Now, that
creates that takes power and that's
going to be expensive. So, if you guys
are just starting out, use a preset.
When you get to use a preset, you'll
have all these options. These are coming
soon. They're not released yet, but the
AI avatar channel is exactly what I use
for Marcus Graves. So, just go ahead and
do AI avatar channel. We're going to
call our AI avatar Lisa Graves. And
we're going to call our niche/topic
um let's describe it. Okay, my niche is
going to be the 50 plus American home.
So, it's going to be classes
products to use or products or perhaps I
don't really know what to put there. You
guys can probably give it a better
prompt than me, but that's all I'm going
to put. Next, we go into avatar look.
Now, we can do two things. We can either
describe with AI and create our whole
avatar within within Rookcast. But what
I would do, I wouldn't create it within
Rookcast. I'd use our hijen avatars.
Now, either you can use a public avatar,
which would be any of these, or you can
go ahead and you can go to your avatars.
These are all my avatars. I'm obviously
going to blur out all of them except for
Lisa Graves, which by this little voice
icon, you can see already has a voice
attached to her. So, when I click here
and I go, let's use Avatar 3. Keep in
mind, these are really expensive. Don't
use these unless you have a lot of
money. This is going to be like a fifth
of the price to use Avatar 3. So, then
when we go to voice, as we can see, we
already have the Hey Gen voice
connected.
>> Hi, I'm excited you're here. This is
your voice clone preview.
>> There we go. Sounds very realistic.
Sounds exactly like this woman looks. It
fits perfectly. Now, of course, we could
go change voice and we could use all
types of stuff, but no, I'm just going
to select my avatar's built-in voice. I
don't want to use any of these ones or
connect my custom 11 Labs API. I'm just
going to do this. Now, content style. I
have two options here. What I could
either do is I could paste in someone
else's content and analyze it. So, in
this case, I could totally take this
woman's, you know, channel and just tell
them to analyze this. But, I'm not going
to do that. I'm actually just going to
do it manually. I'm just going to go
friendly expert. I'm going to go length
three to five minute videos because I
just want to give you guys examples. I'm
not going to create full videos right
now. Typically, you could go for longer.
Um, and by the way, now this is set in
stone. You can always just tell your
agent later to change some of this. So,
let's say I want to make 30 plus minute
long videos. I just have to select this,
but then later on I'm going to tell my
rook, hey, I actually want to make
videos that are over 30 minutes long
instead of over 15. Now, we select this
and we go for our hook style. You can
also change this later on just by
talking to your rook cast, but I'm going
to go with curiosity gap. I always like
to just stick with curiosity gap. That
is the best way to hook an audience. You
create some sort of information gap that
the audience just has to fill in by the
end of the video so they keep watching.
Next, we go to editing styles. This is
how the video is going to be edited once
the avatar video is generated. What is
going to be overlaid? What is going to
be put on top of it? This could be
B-roll. This could be motion graphics.
Um, and yeah, I'm going to use motion
graphics. I personally, you know, B-roll
is good. Actually, for this niche, it
might be great. Um, actually, you know
what? [__] it. All right. I'm going to
use B-roll because actually for this
niche it would be very good. I typically
don't use it but I I like it for this
niche. B-roll. Let's do it. Create
channel. Nice. Lisa Graves is ready.
Generate my first video. Now, as all
this stuff is going to happen, you guys
see I have these options at the bottom.
This lets me select which model I'm
using. I can either use Claude Sonnet,
which is like a pretty good model. It's
a little bit more expensive, or I can
use cheaper ones. The cheaper ones are
going to do a much worse job. If you use
any of these, you're probably going to
burn your credits because the AI is
going to do a shitty job. But I like to
use Sonnet 4.6. It's pretty balanced.
But you can maybe use something cheaper.
Or even if you're feeling it, you can
use something more expensive. But I like
to use Sonnet 4.6. Anyway, also you have
this little button down here that goes
request rem request approval or auto. If
it's on auto, then the agent will just
automatically start creating the entire
workflow for you. Um, and basically
whenever it wants to generate something,
it will just do it without asking you.
Now, I typically use it on auto because
I just like to generate my videos from
start to finish, but you can use it on
request approval for the first channel
you create or the first few channels you
create just at the start to make sure
that it isn't generating anything that
you don't want it to. So, let's see. It
came back with some topics. Five
everyday cleaning products you should
never mix together. I like it. Let's do
it. You know what? Why not? I like that
it's kind of like urgent. It's like I
need to click on it. Honestly, isn't a
great video. Like, it's not something I
would post. Typically, you want to do
your own research and not just take like
an idea from Rookcast. You want to go do
your own YouTube research. But for the
sake of this video, I'm just going to
say yes, that's a great idea. I love it.
Now, I want to alter our workflow
pipeline a little bit. As you can see,
Rook has made this little workflow on
the side here. It has choose a video
topic, generate thumbnail, write video
script. I'm going to edit it a little
bit. I actually want to make my own
thumbnails. I don't want it to generate
thumbnails for me. So, I'm going to tell
it that. Now, also for B-roll and motion
graphics, I'm going to specifically tell
it for B-roll, I want it to only source
stock B-roll for cheap. I don't want it
to generate any AI B-roll cuz AI B-roll
is going to be expensive. So, unless you
specifically want AI B-roll, I would
always tell it, hey, don't use any AI
B-roll. Only use stock B-roll.
First off, I don't just don't worry.
We'll round to step three, which is now
also when you're creating B-roll for
overlaying, I only want you to use stock
for cheap. I don't want you to use any
AI roll that expensive press. So don't
do that, please. Anyway,
there we go. Simple prompt like that.
You literally just talk to it like you
would talk to a human, like you would
talk to chat GBT. It's that simple. We
click enter and watch it do its thing.
All right, guys. So, it's writing the
script for me. It has the voice DNA, you
know, which is like going to be the
archetype and everything like that. Um,
and now it wrote the entire script. And
let's say I just read it over. It looks
good. Typically, honestly, I don't even
read over my script. I just tell it what
to do and then I just like trust that
it's going to do it. You guys can
probably read over your script. I'm
lazy. I like to just go, "Great. I love
it. Good script. Let's go ahead with
that and move on to the next steps of
generating the talking head avatar
video." And of course, going ahead and
adding in those stock B-roll overlays
and motion graphics. Now, it's getting
to work. Um, and what it's going to do
right now is it's going to take that
script and it's going to put it into
your Hen subscription and it's quite
literally going to be generating it
using your Hen account. So, it's going
to go to your Hen account and it's going
to start generating this video for you.
Now, typically if you didn't have your
own Hen account connected, it would use
an API key to Hen. Now, the API key is
much more expensive. The API key just
for Avatar 3 costs a dollar every
minute. Meaning, if you're generating a
30-minute long video, just the just the
avatar video alone, not the motion
graphics, not the script, not anything
else, just the avatar video generating
it is going to cost you $30. Now, if you
connect a Hey Gen account, it's going to
cost you about 10 or under. Actually,
more like I think $5 to $10 just from
Hey Gen. And then the other costs come
up to about $15 to $20 total for a 30
minute long video, which is much much
much better than what you'd be spending
if you didn't connect your Hen account.
So remember that, guys. Connect your Hen
account. All right, we're back. I said,
"How's it going?" And it said it's done
and it has the video ready for me. Here
we go. As you can see,
>> there are two completely ordinary
cleaning products.
>> There we go. It has the video ready.
It's a little bit low quality, but hey,
we're using Avatar 3. Of course, it's
going to be low quality. That's just how
it goes. So, anyway, great. It looks
good. Let's go ahead and now submit the
fulllength video to Hey Gen and um yeah,
get the full thing going.
Nice. So guys, now it's going to go
ahead and get the full thing going.
Let's say I want to step away from my
computer because this is probably going
to take maybe 20 minutes to generate. I
don't really know. 5 minute video
actually might not take too too long.
But let's say I have to leave my house
because I can't sit here doing stuff all
day. When I say it takes 10 minutes to
make a video, I mean you can set it
running and then you can leave your
house because
if you guys didn't know, Rookcast has a
web app that works really great on your
phone. So, as you guys can see, I have
it ready on my phone. I'm just going to
set it generating. And now I can
literally just step away from my
computer. I have it all going on my
phone. So, I can go to the gym. I can go
do whatever. And I can genuinely
complete the rest of this video from my
phone. That's what I love about
Rookcast. You can run tons and tons of
different channels all from your phone
and be generating them and posting them
and doing everything within Rookcast
while you like barely even have to touch
your computer. There we go. As you can
see, full video is generating and we're
going to come back in about 15 to 25
minutes. All right. I'm back and the
video is fully ready now. As you guys
can see right here, we have the Oh, it's
just lagging a bit, but we have the full
avatar video ready right here. I have it
on my phone as you guys can see.
>> And what I'm going to do for you guys,
because as I said, you can walk away
from your computer and you can use your
phone, is I'm just going to kind of show
you that right here. I'm going to go
ahead and use my phone. I'm going to
talk to it.
Okay, great. Go ahead and get started on
the entire motion graphics process. When
it's done, open up Remotion for me so I
can review it. Just work non-stop until
it's all ready for me to review.
All right. And as you can see, I just
gave it that message there. Obviously,
there are some typos in my voice to
speech, but um as you can see right
there, uh it's taking that prompt and
it's doing it all from my phone. It
doesn't need to run on my computer. It
doesn't need to run on anything. I could
be at the beach and I could be making my
YouTube videos for the day just telling
it what to do. It's awesome. I [__]
love Rook. I can manage so many YouTube
channels using it. All right, and that's
about it. It'll take some time. It'll
open the motion studio. You'll be able
to chat back and forth with it to
actually edit the video. Maybe you don't
like the placements of the motion
graphics. You can chat with it, edit all
that. I don't want to bore you guys, but
basically, you'll be able to get the
complete video edited with motion
graphics and B-roll. So, what do you do
now? You have the entire video ready and
made. Now, the last step is thumbnail
and publish. Now, I kind of put
thumbnail in here as a bit of a joke.
The thumbnail is not the last step.
Obviously, the thumbnail is the first
step cuz when you created your video
idea all the way back here, you should
already have a thumbnail already. You
just steal a thumb from a thumbnail from
someone else and you put it in yours but
edited a bit. I used Donald Trump
instead of George Washington because,
you know, Trump was seeming to work in
these other videos. And um everything
else I basically just stole. So yeah,
that's literally it. That simple. take a
thumbnail, steal it from an outlier
video, and then publish for the
description and the tags and all the
YouTube metadata. None of that really
matters. All that matters is the one
thing, the AI checkbox. You know how it
has altered content. And you can either
check yes or no. Now, a lot of people
have been asking me what should they
click. Should they say yes and disclose
it, or should they click no and not
disclose it, but maybe risk getting in
trouble with YouTube? My option is just
don't answer either. YouTube can't get
mad at you if you just didn't answer it.
And if you click yes, they are now
rolling out a feature where it will
literally put an AI watermark right next
to the title of the video. And to be
honest, I don't want that. So, I've just
not been answering anything and it's
been working just fine for me. I'm not
getting demonetized, nothing. So, there
you go, guys. That is the ultimate tip
to creating a YouTube video. Now, I have
one last little thing for you guys. And
this is a bit of a demonetization trick.
And it is this is also a bit of a trick
on how to keep your niche alive. And
that is thumbnail altering. Now, if you
use the same thumbnail every time,
YouTube will often catch up and
potentially demonetize you cuz they see
that you're just kind of spamming out
the same content. So, it's good to
switch up your thumbnail style, and
that's not a bad thing. As you can see,
if I go back to my account, when I've
been switching out my thumbnail style,
it's been working great for me. As you
can see, for a while, I was doing this
exact thumbnail style. It was kind of
working, but my view started to really
die down and tank. So, I came up with a
new style. I found this thumbnail style.
Now, this thumbnail style feels more
like a dash cam video. Maybe you've seen
those police body cam, you know, niches
or whatever. All those different types
of it's completely different style of
YouTube, yet it works really well for my
target for my target audience because
American seniors actually watch a lot of
these body cam videos. So, I took that
thumbnail style and just used it in my
video.
Then after I used that a couple times,
you can see I got some really good
views. And then I decided, hey, I'm
going to try to switch it up one more
time. And that's when I found this
thumbnail style, another really cool one
that I found from another popular
channel. Um, I forget what the exact
name is. Um, but anyway, it was a
similar thumbnail to this and I
basically just copied it with AI. And
what do you know? This has been my best
performing video yet. As you can see,
it's just absolutely blowing up. It's
made me $9,000.
It was posted just a few days ago. And
keep in mind this now this $9,000 is
only up until May 27th. Right now it's
May 28th. And as you can see, it has
been growing from 400,000 views all the
way up to 700,000. Meaning this number
is actually closer to 15,000. It just
hasn't updated yet, which is absolutely
insane, you guys. So, if you want to
learn how to create a channel like this
and or if you want to blow up a channel
like this, re-watch this tutorial, save
it, actually go through the whole thing
again because trust me, guys, this is
the biggest opportunity of your
lifetime. I genuinely can't believe how
much money that I have been making off
my AI channels. So, go ahead, go back,
go through the full workflow, and um
yeah, if you want to actually get really
good and learn this kind of stuff, all
you got to do is go to my Discord
server. We have an awesome Discord
server right here as you can see and
it's all about you know YouTube
automation. Just go check it out.
There's going to be tons of stuff.
There's going to be tools to actually
learn Rook and learn how to use it even
better. So go ahead and join up that
Discord server right now. And yep.